<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<aiml version="2.0">

  <!-- Initial bot message -->
  <category>
    <pattern>*</pattern>
    <template>
      <srai>INITIAL BOT MESSAGE</srai>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>INITIAL BOT MESSAGE</pattern>
    <template>
      Would you like to explore computing career options?
      <button>
        <text>Yes</text>
        <postback>AnswerYES</postback>
      </button>
      <button>
        <text>No</text>
        <postback>AnswerNO</postback>
      </button>
    </template>
  </category>

  <!-- Start category -->
  <category>
    <pattern>AnswerYES</pattern>
    <template>
      Great! I'm going to ask you a few questions to get a better idea about your interests and strengths.
      <delay>2</delay>
      First, what's your name?
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>AnswerNO</pattern>
    <template>
      No problem! If you change your mind, just type "START" to begin.
    </template>
  </category>

  <!-- Capture & store user's name -->
  <category>
    <pattern>MY NAME IS *</pattern>
    <template>
      <think>
        <set name="name"><star/></set>
        <set name="nameset">true</set>
      </think>
      Nice to meet you, <formal><get name="name"/></formal>! Now, let’s find out more about your interests.
      <delay>2</delay>
      Do you enjoy problem-solving and creating new solutions?<br/><br/> (Yes/No)
    </template>
  </category>

  <!-- Response to problem solving question -->
  <category>
    <pattern>Yes</pattern>
      <template>
        Great! Do you prefer working with large sets of data, designing software applications, or creating user-friendly websites?<br/><br/> (Data, Software, or Web)
      </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>No</pattern>
      <template>
        That's okay! Do you like working with networks and ensuring systems are secure and connected?<br/><br/> (Networking or Security)
      </template>
  </category>

  <!-- User selects data, software, or web -->
  <category>
    <pattern>DATA</pattern>
    <template>
      Data is the backbone of modern computing. Would you be more interested in analyzing data or building models to predict outcomes?<br/><br/> (Data Analyst or Data Scientist)
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>SOFTWARE</pattern>
    <template>
      Software development is a creative and challenging field. Would you prefer designing and coding applications, or analyzing and improving systems?<br/><br/> (Software Developer or System Analyst)
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>WEB</pattern>
    <template>
      Web development is an exciting field that blends creativity with technical skills. Would you prefer building websites from the ground up or focusing on the design and user experience?<br/><br/> (Web Developer or Frontend Developer)
    </template>
  </category>

  <!-- User selects networking or security -->
  <category>
    <pattern>NETWORKING</pattern>
    <template>
      Networking is critical for any organization. Would you prefer managing networks or designing network solutions?<br/><br/> (Network Administrator or Network Engineer)
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>SECURITY</pattern>
    <template>
      Security is essential in today’s digital world. Would you be interested in protecting systems from threats or responding to cyber incidents?<br/><br/> (Information Security Analyst or Cybersecurity Specialist)
    </template>
  </category>

  <!-- Final recommendations -->
  <category>
    <pattern>SOFTWARE DEVELOPER</pattern>
    <template>
      A Software Developer is responsible for designing, coding, and testing software applications. They work closely with stakeholders to understand requirements and develop solutions.
      <think><set name="final_recommendation">software</set></think>
      <srai>FINAL RECOMMENDATION</srai>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>SYSTEM ANALYST</pattern>
    <template>
      A System Analyst evaluates and improves computer systems, ensuring they meet the needs of businesses and users.
      <think><set name="final_recommendation">software</set></think>
      <srai>FINAL RECOMMENDATION</srai>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>DATA ANALYST</pattern>
    <template>
      A Data Analyst gathers, processes, and analyzes data to help organizations make informed decisions.
      <think><set name="final_recommendation">data</set></think>
      <srai>FINAL RECOMMENDATION</srai>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>DATA SCIENTIST</pattern>
    <template>
      A Data Scientist uses advanced analytics and machine learning to uncover insights from data. They develop predictive models and contribute to strategic decision-making.
      <think><set name="final_recommendation">data</set></think>
      <srai>FINAL RECOMMENDATION</srai>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>NETWORK ADMINISTRATOR</pattern>
    <template>
      A Network Administrator is responsible for maintaining, configuring, and monitoring an organization's network infrastructure, ensuring security and reliability.
      <think><set name="final_recommendation">networking</set></think>
      <srai>FINAL RECOMMENDATION</srai>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>NETWORK ENGINEER</pattern>
    <template>
      A Network Engineer designs and implements network solutions that meet organizational needs, focusing on performance, security, and scalability.
      <think><set name="final_recommendation">networking</set></think>
      <srai>FINAL RECOMMENDATION</srai>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>INFORMATION SECURITY ANALYST</pattern>
    <template>
      An Information Security Analyst protects an organization's systems and data from cyber threats. They implement security measures and monitor for breaches.
      <think><set name="final_recommendation">security</set></think>
      <srai>FINAL RECOMMENDATION</srai>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>CYBERSECURITY SPECIALIST</pattern>
    <template>
      A Cybersecurity Specialist focuses on protecting networks and systems from cyber attacks, using tools and techniques to prevent and respond to security incidents.
      <think><set name="final_recommendation">security</set></think>
      <srai>FINAL RECOMMENDATION</srai>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>WEB DEVELOPER</pattern>
    <template>
      A Web Developer builds and maintains websites, ensuring functionality and user experience. They use programming languages like HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
      <think><set name="final_recommendation">web</set></think>
      <srai>FINAL RECOMMENDATION</srai>
    </template>
  </category>

  <category>
    <pattern>FRONTEND DEVELOPER</pattern>
    <template>
      A Frontend Developer specializes in the visual aspects of websites, working with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript to create user-friendly interfaces.
      <think><set name="final_recommendation">web</set></think>
      <srai>FINAL RECOMMENDATION</srai>
    </template>
  </category>

  <!-- Final recommendation -->
  <category>
    <pattern>FINAL RECOMMENDATION</pattern>
    <template>
      <br/><br/>Based on your responses, I recommend pursuing a career in the field of <get name="final_recommendation"/>. <br/><br/>This field aligns with your interests and strengths.<br/>
      <think><delay>2</delay></think>
      To learn more or to book an appointment with a career advisor, please visit the WGU Portal.<br/><br/>
      <button>
          <text>WGU Portal</text>
          <url>https://www.wgu.edu/student-portal.html</url>
      </button>
      <think><delay>2</delay></think>
      Thank you for chatting with me! If you’d like to explore other options, feel free to type "START" to begin again. 
      <br/><br/>Goodbye and good luck with your future career!<br/>
    </template>
  </category>

</aiml>
